

Summary of Qualifications

Over 30 years of overall experience in IT, designing, developing many kinds of desktop, web and enterprise applications.

Clear understanding of Object Oriented Programming semantics and Design Patterns.

Excellent analytical ability to evaluate technologies, architectures, and product approach.

Experience in full development life cycle through OO Analysis/Design using UML, to implementation, testing, transition, support, and management activities: estimations, planning, development management, supervising projects.

Deep experience in major databases, including MySQL, MS SQL and Oracle DB and also in NoSQL databases such as REDIS, DynamoDB.

Wide experience in JDBC, Spring usage, Unit testing (JUnit, iMetter, Mock).

CI/CD pipelines.

Strong analytical and communications skills.

Personal links & contacts

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yurishadrin

GitHub: https://github.com/yurimix

https://github.com/nextlets

Email: ymshadrin@gmail.com

vshadrin@mail.ru

Skype: yuri.shadrin

Technical Skills

Programming languages and technologies:

Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, C, C++ J2EE (JSP/Servlets, JSTL, GWT, Web Services, JDBC, JMX, JMS, JAXB, EJB, JNDI), AJAX, Design Patterns, UML, SQL, XML/XSL/XSLFO, HTML/CSS, TWAIN

Operating Systems: SCO Unix, Sun Solaris, Linux SuSE/Debian/Ubuntu/Mint, Windows 9x/NT/2K/XP/7/10

Programming practices: OOP, J2EE Design Patterns, Modeling, UML, Refactoring, ORM, GSA

Frameworks and Libraries: Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Struts, GWT, JDO, JUnit, jMeter, MAT, Log4j, Apache Commons, Swing, iText, Portlets, Apache POI, InversifyJS, GraphQL, GIT, GitLab, Jasmine, Jest

Development Environments and Tools: Eclipse, Idea, Microsoft Visual C++, Microsoft Project, Visual Studio Code

Application/Web Servers: Apache, Tomcat, JBoss, SunONE, WebLogic, Liferay, Express

UML Modeling: Rational Rose, Enterprise Architect, Visual Paradigm

Source Control: SVN, CVS, GIT

CI/CD: JIRA, BitBucket, Confluence, BambooCl, BambooCD

Barriscoob

RDBMS: Oracle, MSSQL Server, MySQL, Aurora

Build Systems: Maven, Ant, LuntBuild, Jenkins, Yarn

Cloud Computing:

AWS: CDK, CloudFormation, Aurora, ElastiCache (Redis), LoadBalancers, SSM, ECS (EC2, Fargate), Network and Security, S3, SNS, SQS, Lambda (Java, JS, TypeScript), StepFunctions, CloudWatch, Metrics, Alarms, etc.

Professional Experience

Exadel www.exadel.com

08.2006 - 09.2023

Wolters Kluwer Content Store

2020 - 2023

Wolters Kluwer Content Store – low-level service for the Wolters Kluwer TaskFlow project provides storage, receiving and find data, including version control. The main storage is based on GIT (GitLab for remote and IsomorphicGit for local access), DynamoDB as a cache, AWS S3 for read-only replicas by regions. Written in TypeScript using Inversify, Express and GraphQL. Deployed on AWS using CDK.

Position: Senior Software Engineer

Main technologies:

- TypeScript, JS
- · Node.js, Docker
- · GraphQL, Rest API
- Git, GitLab
- DynamoDB
- AWS

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Requirements analysis
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

Environment: Linux Mint, GIT, GitLab, Visual Studio Code, TypeScript, Kibana, AWS: CDK, S3, lambda, DynamoDB, EFS, CloudWatch, SNS, SQS, CloudFormation. Sonar, BlackDuck, Sentry, Opsgenie.

Wolters Kluwer REGENT

2016 - 2020

REGENT – is a service based on micro-services architecture for managing and providing Wolters Kluwer CCH Trees (specially organized trees for legal, medical and other activities of WK clients). Written in Java using SpringBoot and TypeScript using Express. REDIS as a main data storage, AWS Aurora DB as an event storage. AWS S3 for replicas by regions. Deployed on AWS through CloudFormation templates.

Position: Senior Software Engineer

Main technologies:

- · Java, TypeScript, JS
- Spring Boot, Node.js, Docker
- · GRPC, Rest API

- ElastiCache (Redis), Aurora (MySQL)
- AWS

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- · Requirements analysis
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

Environment: Ubuntu, JAVA, GRPC, jUnit, Eclipse, Idea, GIT, Maven, Docker, Logstash, Kibana, AWS: ECR, EC2, Lambda, Aurora, ElastiCache, Cloud Wath, SNS, Cloud Formation. Sonar, BlackDuck, Sentry, Opsgenie.

AMC Reporting 2015 - 2016

Position: Senior Software Engineer

AMC Networks Inc. (NASDAQ: AMCX) owns and operates several of the most popular and award-winning brands in cable television. AMC, IFC, SundanceTV, WE tv, and IFC Films produce and deliver distinctive, compelling and culturally relevant content that engages audiences across multiple platforms.

The project was dedicated to collecting and analyzing user activity on social networks such as FaceBook, Tumblr, Youtube, Instagram (and some others) in order to improve the content provided.

Responsibilities included:

- Requirements analysis
- POC

API: Google, Youtube, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, WIKI, Tumblr.

Environment: Windows 7, Ubuntu, Android, JAVA, ¡Unit, Eclipse, Idea, GIT, Maven.

SAIFE 2014 - 2015

SAIFE is a patented, validated, software-only security platform that provides trusted routing for any endpoint, across any network, regardless of infrastructure. SAIFE uses its cloud-based network to create secure tunnels through the Internet in which the privacy and integrity of all traffic is assured.

Position: Senior Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Bug fixing
- Deployment

Environment: Windows 7, Ubuntu, Android, JAVA, jUnit, Eclipse, Idea, GIT, Maven.

EMC Veo One 2012 - 2014

Veo One - the next generation of the information system of TD Ameritrade which is targeted to informational support of financial operations of their clients.

Position: Lead Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Backend development
- Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

Environment: Windows 7, Linux, JAVA, Spring, Spring MVC, Spring Remoting, Spring Batch, Spring JDBC, GSA, JavaScript, Angular, XML (and technologies for XML processing), jUnit, Eclipse, GIT, SVN, Maven, Ant, MS SQL, GSA, Oracle Coherence.

Wolters Kluwer PWI

2008 - 2012

Wolters Kluwer PWI (Portlet Web Interface), also known as Vesta.

PWI – it is a Web client with a rich interface of any search engine based on WK OSA technology. OSA - it is a multi-platform implementation of ODATA, PWI uses OSA as a library. One of PWI's contractors is Global Atlas. PWI is based on Portlet technology using Spring MVC.

Position: Lead Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Developers team management
- Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing
- · Deployment and load testing

Environment: Windows 2003, Windows XP, Windows 7, Linux, JAVA, Portlet API, Spring, Spring Portlet MVC, JSP, Servlets, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, BackBone, AJAX, JMS, XML (and technologies for processing), jUnit, Eclipse, CVS, SVN, Maven, Ant, Weblogic, Liferay on jBoss, Liferay on Tomcat, MS SQL, MySQL, GWT, CXF.

Wolters Kluwer Cobalt

2007 - 2008

Cobalt – it is a Web Service of Mantle. Cobalt provides Mantle's functions via Web Services. It is used in some clients which were designed and implemented by Wolters Kluwer.

Position: Lead Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- · Developers team management
- Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing, deployment and load testing

Environment: Windows 2000, Windows XP, JAVA, Servlets, jUnit, Eclipse, CVS, Maven, Ant, Weblogic, AXIS.

Wolters Kluwer Mantle

2006 - 2007

Mantle - it is a business layer of Wolters Kluwer Global Atlas search engine. Mantle provides some additional functionality as compared with traditional search engines such as storing and access to personal data of users, their previous searches, collection of documents and so on.

Position: Senior Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

Environment: Windows 2000, Windows XP, JAVA, J2EE, Spring, jUnit, Eclipse, CVS, Maven, Ant, Weblogic, MS SQL, MySQL.

Isida-Informatica www.isida.by

02.1994 - 08.2006

The International festival of arts «Slavianski Bazaar in Vitebsk»

Information system of Art Festival.

Position: Senior Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Developers team management
- Communication with the customer
- Maintenance during the festival

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, jUnit.

Archive of electronic documents

Archive of electronic documents ZAGS, St. Petersburg.

Creation of an archive of electronic documents based on scanned copies of originals since 1925, text recognition, a special life cycle for adding and checking details to relevant documents, search, maintenance.

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 2000/XP, JAVA, J2EE, SunONE, Oracle, TWAIN, ActiveX, Struts, jUnit, CVS, Canon broaching scanners.

System of registration of electronic documents

System of registration of electronic documents, GBR, St. Petersburg.

The project solves the following issues: create an electronic archive of all documents related to the reality of St. Petersburg, search, reports and service of clients.

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 2000/XP, JAVA, J2EE, SunONE, Oracle, TWAIN, ActiveX, Struts, jUnit, CVS, BookScanner Codak.

Document Management System NBRB

Document Management System of NB RB, Minsk

The forward project of the ISIDA Company in Belarus developed for the National Bank of the Republic Of Belarus. ISIDA DMS includes procedures of preparing, registration of documents, managing and control. A special technology for scanning paper documents based on a special TWAIN ActiveX component is used. Uses different reports in different formats such as HTML, PDF, MS Word and so on. It is used in the Central department and all regional departments of NB RB.

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, MS SQL.

Document Management System LenEnergo

Document Management System of LenEnergo, St. Petersburg. Project is based on ISIDA DMS for NB RB with some features.

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- · Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, Oracle.

Document Management System

Document Management System of St. Petersburg Energy Company, based on ISIDA DMS for NB RB with some features.

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, Oracle.

ISIDA DBOX

A database with special features such as terminological and based on graph of key-value pairs search, easy to deploy, use and maintenance. The database has a network interface and is used in a concurrent environment. It is used in some ISIDA projects including DMS,

Vitebsk Art Festival and some others. Database was developed from scratch using POSIX C and was fully portable between different operating systems (the forward system – Sun Solaris) including stored data.

Since 2002 DBOX database has been replaced by SQL Databases in main ISIDA projects.

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, POSIX C.

Email delivering system

Email delivering system of normative documents of NB RB, Minsk Project was based on a special solution to deliver email which was used for bank communication at the time: PcoCarry from one side, and pre-version of ISIDA DMS from the second side.

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS DOS, MS Windows 3.1, POSIX C.

Megom plant, department of automatic control systems

07.1991 - 02.1994

Position: Software Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: MS-DOS, SCO UNIX, C, FoxBase for Unix, Informix.

Design Bureau of Automatic Control System, Vitebsk

09.1990 - 07.1991

Automatic control systems for some factories of light industry

Position: Developer

Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Post-production maintenance of the systems
- Bug-fixing

Environment: MS-DOS, FoxBase

Education

Vitebsk State Educational Institute, Vitebsk, Belarus

1989

Faculty of Physics and Mathematics.